Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpat.
I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services. I am an MBA in Finance and have been
working in the corporate sector for 13 years.
Today I am presenting to you the
latest update of ICICI
Protense Life Insurance's Protect
and Gain Term Plus ULIP plan.
What good benefits and
features have come in that plan? Has it become cheaper? By how much
percentage has it become cheaper? Is
it the best in comparison to competitors like Tata or HDFC?
So, I have
also compared it with TADAC in the video.
Plus, IIC Prosil has launched a new fund. The
name of that fund is Multi Cap 50 25
25. I have also explained this new fund along with this plan.
You can invest in this fund at an NV of ₹10 and
can also get the highest returns. So, here
you will get higher returns, insurance
cover and tax benefits as well.
In 1010D, you will get tax free investment.  You will also
get income. Watch the full video. If you like the video, you
can take insurance cover of 125 times the premium on my YouTube4. The second
change is that after 26 years, you will get
four times the mortality, not double.
No insurance in the industry is refunding four times the mortality charges in a UL policy
or in such term plus UL policy,
but in this plan,
this benefit has also been made available to you. Plus,
as a maturity booster at 20%, the
additional fund value of the average fund value of the last 3 years at the end of the policy will be
added to your maturity. So,
this booster will also be added which was there earlier and is
still available. The biggest limitation in the old Protect and Gain was that
you could take only up to Rs 1 crore. Plus, the
premium was also a little higher and the video medical
limit was also up to Rs 1 crore. In the new
Protect and Gain, there is
no limit on the maximum sum asset. You
can take Rs 2 crore, Rs 5 crore or Rs 10
crore.  You can also take it, it depends upon your
financial eligibility and health.
Secondly, the pricing premiums have been
reduced by around 16 per cent. The
premiums have been reduced from 16 to 25 per cent.
Plus, you are also getting video MR and income
waiver up to 2 crores. If
you take cover up to ₹ crores,
you can also get video medical done instead of physical medical. Plus, the
option of income proof waiver is also
given in these policies. Now, how much
change has come in the premium in the new version? For example, if a
person is 30 or 35 years old and is
taking a premium payment term of 10 years and purchases a
policy term of 40 years, then
here, if he had taken an insurance cover of 50 lakhs
in the earlier version, then you would have had to pay a premium of ₹ 603.
Now you have to
pay a premium of ₹ 2603. The
premium has been reduced by 16 per cent. If you were
taking an insurance cover of 1 crore at that time, then you would have had to pay a
premium of ₹ 2205.  Right now you are
getting a premium of only ₹ 5205, so
ICICI Potential has reduced the premium significantly,
as you know this
policy is an equity based policy ULIE
plan, so there is a facility of partial withdrawal as well, you can do
partial withdrawal up to 20% of your fund value, plus you can take the benefit of
SWP, you can also
take the benefit of Systematic Withdrawal Plan, after 5 years both these facilities become
available, you
can take partial withdrawal as well as
SWP, for
example, you said that my fund value
for example is ₹ lakh and I want a percentage of 20 lakh to
come automatically in my account every year, then it will come
to 6, if you said it should come to 8, then it will
come to 8, if you said it should come to 10, then it will
come to 10, whatever percentage of amount
you select, whatever percentage you select,
you will get that percentage of fund value every
year every month  If you want to take quarterly or semi-annual withdrawals,
you can do it and
can also do systematic withdrawals. For
example, you are getting ₹20 lakh interest,
but if
you need another ₹1 lakh,
you
can also do an additional partial withdrawal of ₹2 lakh at that time. IIC Ltd has
launched a new fund in March 2024. It is an
excellent fund. Multi Cap 50 25 25 Large
Cap Mid Cap Small Cap. At 50,
your investment will be in large cap, at 25 in mid cap
and at 25
in small cap. So, at 50, when you go into large cap,
large cap means top
100 companies of India, the top 100 companies are in it, then
your risk reduces a bit and
stability increases. Similarly,
for growth, you are investing in small cap and mid cap at 25.
Your investment is in small cap and mid cap.
Investment is also being made in this, plus you are
also getting diversification. You will also be investing separately
in more than 500 stocks in more than 500 sectors.
If you look at this picture, how will your money be
invested? Your
weightage of 50 will go to large cap, that is,
your investment will be in Nifty 100 stocks.
At 25, your money will be invested
in Nifty Mid Cap 150 stocks, your
investment will be in mid cap and the
weightage of 25 will be in small cap stocks.
If you look at this picture, the companies from first one to
100 are large cap. The
companies from 101 to 500
come in mid cap and small cap. So here
your money will be invested in i bank. You are
also getting the benefit of ACL, Godrej, Kotak, TCS insurance and term
plan. You
also get the option to invest in different large cap, mid cap, small cap funds.
Funds:
You can invest in any of the 21 funds given to you and
can switch.
If you go to switch to a mutual fund,
you will incur charges. Here, there is
free of cost switching. There is
insurance cover as well. There is
tax benefit in section ATC of income tax.
You will get tax free income in 1010D.
Long term capital gains tax has to be paid in mutual funds.
Here, you will not have to pay any tax.
Now, this multi-cap index fund will
invest in different sectors here,
like your investment in financial services will be at 26.3,
your
investment in IT sector will be at 9.24, your investment in
capital goods will be at 8.01,
you will invest in oil and gas consumer sector at 7.41,
health care is at 7.34,
auto companies are at 6.38, construction is at 3.14,
services are at 2.13, there is
also investment in textile at 63,
your investment in real estate will also be at 6.41.  It will
also be in services.
Your money will be invested in different companies from different sectors
where you can
get excellent returns. This new
index fund has been launched, Nifty 500 Multi
Cap. If you look at the last 3-year return of this fund, it
is 23.7, the 5-year return
is 19.8, the 10-year return is 17.7
and the last 19-year return is 125. So, as
I told you in the benefit illustration here,
your maturity is
around 8, whereas the actual
returns of your fund can be so good.
Purchase the policy before the 20th. You will
get this fund at an NV of 10. After that,
you can purchase it at whatever NV rate is written.
Here you
can also see in the news. In different news, you
can also see the statements of CEOs of different big companies that this is the time
of India. India's GDP will
grow very fast comparatively as
compared to other countries.  Our country is
growing very fast, so when our
country grows, our country's companies will grow,
your funds will grow, your money will also
grow. So, the
new updated version of Protect
and Gain has come in March 2024. Now,
how will you benefit from it?
Let's understand the benefit registration. Let's assume that there is
a 40-year-old person
named Anil Rajput. His Anil Rajput is
paying a premium for Truffle FS for 1 year
and is taking a 40-year policy term,
where he will have a natural cover of Rs 1 crore,
accidental death cover of Rs 1 crore,
disability cover of Rs 1 crore.
Here his premium will come.
After adding GST and riders, the
premium will come to Rs 8225. The
benefits will run for 12 years and will last for the entire 40 years.
ICICI has sold around 7.72 crore policies so far.
You can see all the other benefits and details here. So,
now let's understand how it
works. I will try to explain a little from here.  I will say
that your invested amount will be Rs
80,000, the rest will be for riders and their
premiums. Suppose your
premium allocation charges are deducted in the first year if Rs
9,600 is deducted, then you will get double of that i.e. Rs 9,200. In column number
you will see Return of Premium Allocation
Charges, in that you will get back its amount. In the
second year if Rs
4,000 is deducted then you will get Rs 8,000 back. In the third year if Rs
3,400 is deducted then you will get Rs 6,800 back. Now the
important thing is that premium allocation
charges are deducted only for three years, not for 12
years. It is not deducted every year. The
big thing is that you have to pay
premium allocation charges only for three years and
not for 12 years. The second good thing is
that here
you get double of Rs 36,000 i.e. for the mortality charges deducted, say Rs 8,000,
and ICICI Bank is the only
company which returns four times the mortality charge in this type of product at the age of 26.
But you will notice that
your mortality charge of 298 552 has been refunded four times
because your
mortality was deducted at the age of 16. If you see here that in the
seventh year you will see that the mortality
charges deducted from you were 74000, so
if you calculate four times of 7468, you will
see that 298
500 has been refunded to you. Similarly, every
year from the age of 26 to 40, you are getting
four times the mortality charges refunded.
Secondly, the mortality charges will be levied on the
sum at risk, that is, there will be a difference between your
insurance cover and the fund value.
Mortality
charges will be levied on that basis. Third and the most important thing I will
tell you is that as per the IIDA norms,
insurance companies
cannot give you on-table returns more than 8%, but
if above 8%, when the company ICICI is
returning all these charges etc. to you four times, then
their net worth comes to 10.24%.
This is the table from 10.24 and the actual return
fund performance is more than 151.
You must have seen the returns of the new fund that was launched. If
you buy that new fund which
is available for ₹10 till 20th March,
you will get more benefit from it. So here if
I show in the comparison how much is the net return in this competition,
for example,
I am taking a sample of Tata's policy and if you
look at the sample of Tata's policy, then
you will see here that on the table at 8, the net return is
7.80, so a company like Tata is giving a net return of 7.80,
but the net return that you are getting from ICICI is
10.24,
so this is also on the table, on paper, or on the
contract. Okay, so four times the
mortality charges, allocation charges are being
deducted for three years. Sum risk p
is the mortality charges for you and here you have
another benefit that your fund value
which is yours  The fund value will remain for the last three
years,
you will also get an age booster benefit of 20% of the fund value of those years.
This booster benefit is also a very healthy
amount, you can see that
you have got an additional booster benefit of 1674990
because the last 71 lakh, 82 lakh
and this 6662 lakh, if you calculate the average of these three years,
this fund value is for every year, then
when you do it at 20%, it comes to
167900, you are also getting this
booster benefit which is not there in most of this company's
such products, there are no
mortality charges, you get four times,
maximum insurance also, in this you
can take one crore, two crore, 10 crore
or even more, if your financial
underwriting is good, your income is good,
then you can also make that purchase, so
you have seen how the
benefit illustration works for you,
now if you see and compare
ICICI Protect and  The
Smart Protect plan of ADFC of Gain and the
Param Rakshak Pro of Tata A are all three plans where the
premium increases for 5 years. The
insurance cover benefit in the policy is
for 40 years. The insurance
cover is of natural cover of 50 lakhs, accidental cover of 50 lakhs and
disability cover of 50 lakhs.
Suppose the age of the customer is 25 years and
he pays premium for 5 years and
takes a policy term of 40 years, then the premium in ICICI will be Rs.
67349 for 5 years
and as per the % on maturity, the premium will be Rs.
174678. So, in ADFC,
you have to pay a premium of Rs. 880000 as against Rs. 67000.
In TA, you have a premium of Rs. 67000
but the fund value of TA is Rs. 768
which is approximately Rs. 1 lakh less. The fund value is
with ICICI. If a
person takes the policy at the age of 30, the
premium increases for 5 years. So, in ICICI,  The
premium is ₹67,1000 in ADAC. A
premium of ₹101,572 will have to be paid. A
premium of ₹81,000 will have to be paid in TA.
Even after paying a premium of ₹81,000, the
maturity is ₹85,000, whereas in IIC only ₹66,000 has to be paid
and the maturity is also ₹1,89,000. If you
look at the age of 35, the premium of IIC will be ₹
94,000. The premium of ADAC will be ₹
1,18,000. The premium of TA will be ₹1,6000.
Here also you should see the fund value, ₹1,690,000
and the fund value of ICICI is ₹37 lakh. At the
age of 40,
ICICI is charging a premium of ₹1,88,000. The
premium will be ₹1,42,000. The
premium in ADAC will be ₹41,000. There is a big difference in the fund value in TA here
too, if the age is 45, the
age is 45.  If you pay premiums every year and are
covered for 40 years, the premium will be ₹52,000
in ECIC, ₹166,000
in HDFC Life and ₹90,000
in Tata's Param Rakshak. If
you compare the premiums among the competitors,
you will see that
ICICI is the winner here. If there is a
premium payment term in the Pay Pay policy, then finally, if
I were to review this product, its new features and the new index fund, it is an excellent
product. The premiums have been reduced,
you can purchase high sums. The fund
value is also comparatively much better.
Its net benefit is 10 point something percentage.
If you look at the last performance of the new
index fund that was launched,
its returns are coming up to 15, 20, 25. You are getting the
benefit of ATC and tax benefit.
Tax free income is coming in 10%.
Like term insurance, your pure insurance
cover is also being provided.  You are
also getting accidental cover benefit, you are also getting disability benefit cover
and after comparing it, it has been seen that
this product is proving to be good in front of the rest of the competitors as well,
but I am
leaving some questions for you, the
comparison that I have presented for you is done on
F Pay, is
ICICI's product number one in 6 Pay, 7 Pay, 10 Pay, 12 Pay also, is
Tata giving better returns in 12 Pay
or is HDFC
giving more or is ICICI giving more,
if a term policy of Rs 2 crore is
taken, then which company's will be better,
in which company the criteria of education and income is
according to your need,
in which company is it mandatory to be 12th pass,
which company is giving policy to 5th pass as well, from
where can you know all these things, you can
contact me, my
mobile number is 9094 3412, you can
buy the policy after comparison, you can get benefit of lakhs of rupees, for
example, if you are sick
You don't select a hospital,
you select a doctor. Similarly,
when you are buying an investment policy,
you should take advice from a person who does right investment
financial planning
because that doctor
looks after your physical health and
your financial consultant is a
doctor of your financial health.
Right financial planning, right financial
advice can give you a lot of profit.
Contact me to compare and purchase the policy. If you like the video, then
definitely subscribe to my channel Anil Rajput FAFS.
Jai
Hind
and